To talk about objects, let's talk about classes.
So, every thing in Python is an instance, all the variables that we've been working with have been instances of a class.
So, for integers, you know, to make a new one, I could just pass in a number to the into constructor.
And if I check the type of that, we'll see that it's a class int.
Something we haven't done is check the type of int itself.
So, a bit different. The class is a type.
Classes versus instances that this OP programming paradigm structured around them.
You can think of a class as a type of something.
Here, the type is an int or you can think about, you know, specific instance of something like a car.
Or I'm sorry, you can think of a specific class or category of something like a car.
And then the instance is the, it's a specific instance of something.
So, here, you know, int is the type.
It's a class whereas the int of five, this is now an instance.
This is V number five.
So, if my class was a car, you might think of an instance being of it being a specific thing like my Subaru.
Right? A class is kind of like a template or a recipe.
And then you can use that to make new active instances that have specific values in them.
When you change a class variable, that's only going to change what's returned from that variable for everything.
But if you change the value of something in an instance, you're not changing the type, you're not changing the recipe or only changing that particular instance that you have.
So, I'm going to come back to this later.
It's a little bit confusing, but those of you who've been doing Python for a while, you might have seen this self keyword,
Peppered throughout code. So, let's talk a little bit about what that does.
If I try to just put code in a new file, no syntax highlighting, so I have to save it.
I'm going to save it as a cars.py.
Okay, so my class car, I have a class method here, wrongs equal true, and start method here, takes a name, or it takes the self.
And I also wanted to take a name for my car.
This time I want to show you that self is associated with the instance.
If I wanted to save the name that I pass into this method, I would do that by saying self.name equal name.
And now I can say if self.runs print car is started, and I'm going to put my F in here this time and the name of the car.
Because name is passed into here, we know that we'll have it, but if we wanted access to it in a method,
that didn't necessarily take this as a parameter, we can use self.name.
That'll give other methods access to it.
And then I can say otherwise print the F string, put the F in there now.
Self.name, car is broken. Oh no.
We'll talk about imports a little bit more later. I might have to restart my repel in order to pick up this new file.
Now, it should be able to do from cars import car.
And if you all are put this car's file in your top level directory, you should be able to do that as well.
Okay. Now I can say, you know, I can check the type of car.
It's a class type. I can look at car and see the runs, the value of runs, because that's a class variable.
But if I try to check car.name, there's no attribute name, that's an instance attribute.
So I'm going to make a new instance and say my Subaru is a new car.
The type of my Subaru.
It's an instance of class cars.car.
Now I can say my Subaru.runs and pass in the string Subaru.
What is going on?
The whole object is not callable.
Oh, thank you so much. Such a total brain fart.
Okay. My Subaru dot start Subaru.
There we go.
Ta-da.
So my Subaru car is started.
I know that when I tried to check the type, so car.name, I got an error.
What if I ask for my Subaru dot name, what will I get?
The Subaru, right? So that variable is associated with the instance, not with the class type.